I think the machine is my
best chance of getting home,
and Walter is not gonna
help me recalibrate it,
so I'm hoping
that Walternate will.
I need to cross over
into the alternate universe.
Put your hands
behind your head.
Don't move!
Our universe
has been infiltrated
by shape-shifters
from your side,
and your Defense Secretary
is behind them.
We'll sort it out
at headquarters.
Nobody knows
you're here but us.
Secretary Bishop,
I came here because I needed
your help to get home.
And I will do
everything in my power,
but you must go back
to the other side and tell them
whoever's behind this
is a threat to us all.
We're chasing the story
of a suspect
locked in a broom closet.
What if he's right?
What if he's not?
We have to tell
Broyles something.
They're on their way
to you now.
We'll be waiting for them.
(Man) I'm telling you,
you're making a mistake.
Your Defense Secretary
is covering his tracks.
He has been
inside your divi--
[beeping]
Downloaded from www.opensubtitles.org
[Beeping]
[Beep]
[Elevator bell dings]
Colonel Broyles.
Mr. Secretary.
What are you
doing here, sir?
I understand
you have a detainee--
Agent Lincoln Lee
from the other side.
That's right.
Who's this?
Please see that Agent Lee
is released immediately.
As far as the rest...
Well, perhaps best
I explain in private.
[Phone ringing]
Shape-shifters?
You're certain
about this?
I wouldn't be here
if I weren't.
And if the Department of Defense
can be infiltrated,
then clearly every branch
of our government is vulnerable.
You're suggesting
that Fringe--
We have reason to believe
that your Agent Murphy
may have been one of them.
We'll know for sure
as soon as he's autopsied.
Do we have any idea
who they're answering to?
No.
Nor do we understand
their end...
What their agenda is.
We might know more soon.
Agents Lee and Dunham
ran a trace
on Murphy's
last phone call.
They're following up
as we speak.
[Distant siren wails]
I don't know.
I've known Murphy
since the Academy.
He's always been
a straight arrow.
Oh, I just got
kind of a hunch
that this other Lincoln's
telling us the truth.
Must be because he has
such a trustworthy face.
[Laughs]
See, I think
he's kind of funny-looking.
You're funny-looking.
[Chuckles]
[Door slams]
(Bolivia)
Don't move.
Put your hands up.
Do you know
what she is?
A shape-shifter.
She was once just
a human being
like any other.
Until you killed her.
Oh, she's not dead.
Though
in a manner of speaking,
she was.
A bookkeeper
for an accounting firm--
can you imagine anything
more lifeless?
I suppose
this is what is feels like
to have a child...
To love
as a parent does.
You must be very proud.
Oh, I am...
Of all of them.
47 so far.
And each one...
Perfect.
[Gurgling]
I'm so sorry.
[Shape-shifter gasping]
What are you doing to it?
To her!
Isn't it obvious.
[Grunting]
Now I'm killing her.
[Shape-shifter grunting]
Why'd you do that?
Because you don't know me
or what I'm capable of.
But if I'm willing to do that
to someone I love dearly,
imagine what I'll do to people
I don't care about.
And what is it you need?
From you?
Nothing.
You don't have
the authority.
Take me to your leader.
[Mysterious music]
♪ Fringe 4x09 ♪
Enemy of My Enemy
Original Air Date on January 20, 2012
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
♪
[Old R&B music]
How's the cheese coming?
Is it done soaking yet?
Ah!
Agent...Dunham.
Hey.
[Electricity buzzing]
Look...
Spherical pastrami.
You hungry?
Uh...
No. [Chuckles]
Thank you.
Um, I was looking
for Astrid.
Hey.
Walter's just discovered
molecular gastronomy.
I liquefied the meat,
then placed it
in an alginate bath.
It's--it's really quite...
Disgusting.
That's the thing
about scientific inquiry--
not every experiment
is a success.
[Smacks bag]
But I hold high hopes
for the parmesan ice cream.
You've had a fun day?
The best.
[Chuckles]
What's up?
I was hoping you could do
something for me.
Uh, could you check
this blood sample
against the national
and international databases?
Am I looking for anything
in particular?
I don't know--
a name, a genetic marker,
anything
out of the ordinary.
What's going on?
You seem troubled.
I helped Peter and Lincoln
cross over
to the other universe.
Since Walter's refusing
to help Peter get back
to where he's from,
he thinks that Walternate
may help him.
And Lincoln's doing recon
on the shape-shifters.
Whoa.
And what does that have to do
with the blood sample?
Probably nothing,
but can you call me
if you find anything?
- Mm.
- And wish me luck.
Where are you going?
Why do you need luck?
Because Broyles doesn't know
anything about this, does he?
And Peter and Lincoln
should have been back by now,
so I'm gonna have to go and
tell him what's been going on.
[Chuckles]
Good luck.
[Siren wails]
What do we know?
That he is certifiable.
Apart from that,
nothing else.
I.D.?
(Alt. Lincoln) We didn't find a show-me--
no surprise there.
We ran his biometrics
through all the databases--
criminal, medical,
insurance.
Based on his accent, we even
reached out to Scotland Yard.
So far, nothing.
- Anything at the location?
Cleared it out
before we got there.
Science Division's
doing a sweep.
He knew we were coming.
I mean, he was waiting
for us to show up.
Take him to interrogation.
I'll meet you there.
And this time
use an actual room,
not the maintenance closet.
Yes, sir.
[Indistinct chatter]
Thanks.
[Phone ringing]
You hear they're bringing up
the suspect?
What suspect?
The guy who's behind
trying to have us killed,
the guy behind
the shape-shifters.
Sir, your escort
should be here shortly.
Thank you.
What escort?
We're leaving.
[Scoffs]
Wait a minute--we might
finally get some answers.
We should stay here,
and we should assist
with the interrogation.
- [Chuckles] No.
I finally got Walternate
to agree to help me.
I don't think the way
to say thank you
is to tell him
how to do his job.
So that's it.
Yeah, you...
- You got what you wanted.
- Yes, I got what I wanted.
And whatever he finds out
in that interrogation
he's gonna share with you.
So you got
what you came for.
And now all I want to do
is get back to the other side,
study the blueprints--
I need to be a part
of this investigation.
I lost partner.
I lost a universe!
You're scared.
Yes, I am scared.
I'm scared that every day
that I stay here
the people that I love
get farther and farther
away from me.
So let them do their jobs.
There's nothing
that you can do here
that they can't do
for themselves.
Is the interrogation
room ready?
What is it?
You know that guy?
I'm Colonel Broyles.
I'd like to ask you
some questions.
I'm sure you have
an abundance of questions.
But I doubt
I'd answer any of them.
Besides which,
we don't have much time.
I imagine you'd like
to avoid unnecessary deaths.
We're not in the business
of responding to threats.
Oh, I wouldn't call
it that.
Consider it an...
Insurance policy.
[Breathing heavily]
An Agent of mine--
a shape-shifter posing
as Dr. Brandon Fayette--
was taken off-line
earlier today.
In his office,
above his desk,
there is a light fixture.
Remove the outer frame.
Tucked inside,
there is a hard drive
you have 12 minutes
to bring it to me.
- 12?
- Not to worry.
I've been assured that
by helicopter,
you can make it
to the D.O.D. and back
with two minutes to spare.
(Alt. Broyles)
And what's on the hard drive?
Go.
We'll call
on our way back.
(Jones)
Nothing of interest to you,
though I'm sure you'll
copy the contents
before you let me go.
Before we let you go?
Of course.
Anything else you want
while we're at it?
Um...
I wouldn't mind
a cup of tea.
[Door opens]
I imagined you'd be
on your way back home.
I know who that man is.
His name
is David Robert Jones.
Go on.
He's a scientist.
He has a background
in biotechnology
and genetic weaponry.
If you're right, we'll have
a record of him--we don't.
He's not in any database.
Because he's not
from your universe.
He crossed over
from the other side.
How can you be so certain?
You've already that things are
different from your timeline.
Let me talk to him.
Sir, I hardly think
that's wise.
[Buzzer sounds]
Do you have my tea?
Hardly.
I do have some questions
I'd like to ask you, though.
Funny...
The last man in here
said the same thing.
You're not from here,
are you?
Did the accent give it away?
[Chuckles]
No.
Actually,
it was the scars.
[Device beeps]
Did you see that?
His pulse just went up.
(Peter)
The last time I saw you,
you were completely
falling apart--
molecular disintegration
due to transporting
out of a German prison.
They had to wrap you
in bandages
just keep you from turning
into a puddle on the floor.
It seems like you figured out
a way to heal yourself.
Do you mind if I ask?
What was it--
some sort of...
DNA graft?
I've never met you
in my life.
No.
But I've met you.
Where?
When you were crossing
out of your universe
into this one.
You created
a-a doorway, a portal.
I'm the man
who closed it on you.
It cut you right in half.
[Scoffs]
Interesting story.
Yet I'm still
in one piece.
I believe
you've run out of time.
[Phone ringing]
This is Broyles.
(Man) Sir, I have
a woman on the line
who says you're
expecting her call.
She says she's a friend
of Mr. Jones.
Go ahead.
(Woman) Is Secretary Bishop
on the line too?
Who is this?
Can Mr. Jones
hear me as well?
[Phone beeps]
(Alt. Broyles)
He can.
(Walternate)
What do you want?
Just for you to listen.
[Indistinct chatter]
Dr. Samuels, do you want me
to give that little girl
with the bike injury
a tetanus?
Not necessary.
I don't think
she's gonna make it.
[Gas hissing]
[People coughing]
(Man)
Oh, my God.
[Panicked chatter]
[Girls screams]
Help! Help!
(Woman)
Help! Let me out of here!
[People screaming
over intercom]
[Knock on glass]
Yes?
Uh, sir,
can I speak to you?
Is this about Peter
and Agent Lee?
You know?
That you helped them
cross over to the other side
without my authorization?
Yes, I know.
I've just received word
from my alter ego.
Needless to say,
he was about as amused as I am.
- Are they okay?
- They're fine.
And we'll deal with the issue
of your insubordination
once we've resolved
the situation.
What situation?
Take a seat.
Have you ever heard of a man
named David Robert Jones?
- No.
- Neither had I.
He's been
in Frankfurt prison
for possession
of state secrets.
Three years ago,
he broke out.
Apparently, since then,
he's made his way
to the other side.
(Bolivia) There were 16 people
in the E.R.--
all of them dead.
And he says, if he's not
released within 14 minutes,
then next attack
will be worse.
What do you want
to do, sir?
- Prepare him for release.
- (Lincoln) What?
You can't be serious.
I understand
your concerns, Agent.
I can't in good conscience
allow him to continue
to attack civilian targets.
And you think capitulating
is going to make him
any less dangerous?
Tell them.
Tell them this
is a terrible idea.
What idea?
They're gonna let Jones
just walk right out of here.
Do we even know
what's on the hard disk?
Apparently, he was accessing
government satellites.
Astrid's reviewing
the data now.
Obviously,
we'll be keeping him
under constant surveillance.
This situation may even play out
to our advantage.
We may learn
who he's working with,
where the other
shape-shifters are.
We can monitor him
with an internal tracker.
- That's a good idea.
- I'm glad you like it.
I put one in his tea.
(Alt. Broyles)
Agent Lee, Dunham...
Start organizing
the surveillance detail.
I'd like to help...
If that's okay with you.
Any objections?
None.
[Phone ringing]
[Indistinct chatter]
[Handcuffs clicking]
Much better,
thank you.
The hard drive, please.
It's been a pleasure.
[People speaking indistinct]
(Alt. Lincoln over comm)
Hey, Red, you got anything?
Uh, yeah.
I mean, same as you.
I'm looking at a guy
who knows he's being watched.
He's gonna make a move
soon, though.
Check your watch.
He's waiting
for the lunch crowd.
He's gonna try
and get lost.
I'll be waiting.
So you two seem close.
Yeah, we are.
Oh, no, no.
[Laughing]
No, I mean, not--
just as partners.
You don't have
to say it like that,
like you pity us.
No, I just
broke up with someone,
and Lincoln's been
my shoulder to cry on.
[Phone ringing]
(Bolivia)
He just got up.
What's he doing?
I'm guessing
that's not lunch.
(Alt. Broyles)
All units be advised--
suspect removed
some kind of thermos
from the trash.
Place Hazmat and E.O.D.
personnel on standby.
Hello.
Would you like some money?
- For real?
- Oh, yes.
But I need your help
giving away all of it.
You see, I've realized
that there's
no point being...
The richest man
in the cemetery.
Huh.
All right.
This guy's giving out
free money!
[Crowd chattering excitedly]
Are you seeing this?
Yeah, I see it.
What the hell's he up to?
[Beeping]
Oh, no.
Colonel Broyles...
We have a problem.
- What is it?
- The tracking software--
there's some sort
of malfunction.
Jones's tracking signal
is multiplying.
We're seeing 40 or 50 dots
and counting.
It's the money.
He knows he's being tracked.
- He's put trackers on the money.
- What?
How the hell did he know
what signal we're using?
Damn it.
All units,
move into the Plaza
and maintain a visual
on the target.
Excuse me!
Fringe Division!
(Bolivia over comm)
Astrid, is there any way
you can zero in on Jones?
I don't know
which signal is his.
I don't see him.
Okay, I think I got him.
There's a new cluster
of trackers
forming by the fountain
north of the Plaza.
Damn it.
It just disappeared.
(Bolivia over comm)
Colonel Broyles, we lost him.
Roger that.
All personnel
return to Fringe Division.
[Piano playing softly]
♪
Walter, I know whatever happened
today was a setback.
[Sighs]
There's more than that.
We were
severely compromised.
Another, please.
And more scotch
is gonna change that?
It was my decision,
Elizabeth.
I knew the risk.
I took a--
an immense gamble.
And now
that man Jones is gone.
I don't think that's
all you're upset about.
You've gone over
the blueprints, haven't you?
Like Peter asked you to.
Yes.
I've tried to see
what he's saying...
That the machine is...
capable of more
than one function,
that it can return him
to his timeline.
But I can't help him.
And apparently,
the other Walter refuses to...
Which is...
Ironic,
given the lengths that
that man went to in the past.
That is not your fault.
It never was.
Well, the outcome
is still the same.
I couldn't save
our son then.
And I can't help him now.
Maybe I can.
Maybe I can help Peter.
These are all the files
we got from the hard drive.
It seems Mr. Jones
was using D.O.D satellite
and ground-penetrating radar
to gather geological
information.
So he's looking
for something underground.
What's there--
minerals, oil deposits?
Nothing of obvious value.
I've cross-referenced
the subfolders
to see which locations
they researched the most,
but so far, I haven't found
any meaningful pattern.
Let me know if you do.
Yes, sir.
Do you mind if I take a look
at your list of locations?
I don't mind.
Are you really
from another timeline?
Yeah, I think so.
Cool.
(Bolivia)
Hey, Lincoln, it's me.
We're uploading Jones'
face-recognition profile
to the surveillance net now.
No, they're detailed.
We got some photos
from the interrogation.
Okay, well,
call me when you do.
[Comm chirps]
Any progress?
Nothing yet, no.
You got something
on your mind?
Actually, yeah.
That tracker
we had on Jones--
how did he pinpoint
the wavelength we were on
that quickly?
What, you think someone
from our team told him?
You have a better idea?
(Astrid)
I'm sorry to interrupt.
That man, Peter--he says
he knows where Jones is going.
I think he was looking
for a mineral
named Amphilicite.
It's found mostly under
sizeable deposits of limestone.
I overlooked
its significance.
Because on its own,
it has no significance.
In its natural state,
it's inert.
It's not really reactive,
like helium.
But if you know how
to process it properly,
it can be used as a power source.
- How do you know all this?
Because where I'm from,
William Bell used
a tiny amount of it
to create a battery.
Jones stole the battery.
A battery made
out of rock?
Yes, trust me,
with this stuff,
you get a lot of bang
for your buck.
Well, how much bang
are we talking?
Enough to blow a hole
in the universe.
I'm guessing Jones must have
figured out the same process
that Bell did and possibly
how to weaponize it.
Which is why
he's looking for it.
Any idea where
he plans on getting it?
Of all the locations
he was studying,
the one with the most potential
for Amphilicite
is located...
[Computer beeps]
Here.
(Lincoln)
The Hudson River Valley.
Right, and this is the map file
they accessed the most
on Dr. Fayette's hard drive--
the Mohonk Quarry.
We contacted the quarry.
They said they haven't seen
any signs of trouble.
Which means we may finally be
one step ahead of him.
Contact Agent Lee.
I want that quarry
secured immediately.
Yes, sir.
We're on the scene.
(Alt. Broyles) We've got the main
entrance secured
and the quarries cleared.
[Device beeps]
(Bolivia) Looks like we
beat Jones to it.
Soil is undisturbed--
no signs of excavation
for the last two months,
at least.
Good.
(Alt. Broyles)
Let's secure the ridge line.
Take up positions
on the western edge.
No one gets
in or out.
Can you patch me through
[computer beeps]
You're on.
There's an access road
above the quarry.
It'd be easy for Jones
to outflank you
if you don't guard it.
What access road?
It's just to the north
of your position.
There's no road.
I'm looking right at it.
Is this the map
that we downloaded
from Dr. Fayette's
hard drive?
It is.
Why?
We're in
the wrong universe.
(Man)
Corridor tracking is complete.
Do it.
[Breathing heavily]
[Breathing deeply]
Something about the air
on this side--
it tastes sweeter.
Tail to the west
makes weather best,
and a tail to the east
makes weather least.
I told Astrid
she wouldn't need an umbrella.
Excuse me, Dr. Bishop.
You have a visitor.
Not now.
Can't you see we're
working on something
very important.
[Footsteps approaching]
Walter?
I'm not her.
You know that, don't you?
Of course.
You're from the other side.
I never expected
to see you again.
I suppose
it's appropriate that...
A version of our son
should bring us together.
I came here for Peter.
I understand you're refusing
to help him.
I'm sorry
you traveled so far.
I can't.
I have made my position
quite clear.
The last time I saw you,
you had come
to save a boy's life.
Now I've come to do the same.
Welcome home.
For the record,
this was my idea.
Later.
There's a chopper waiting.
The tech team is already
en route to the location.
We'll meet them there.
How much trouble
you in?
On a scale
of one to ten?
A lot.
I'm sorry.
It'll blow over.
It's not the first time.
Thank you.
I-I used honey
instead of sugar.
I-I thought--
but if you would
prefer otherwise--
Actually, I prefer honey.
She did too...
my Elizabeth.
My being here must remind you
of so many things.
I'm reminded
of something too...
Of that night
26 years ago...
When you came to me
on the other side
and took Peter
away with you.
I'm sorry.
I should never
have done so.
You were trying
to save him.
He wasn't mine to save.
I had no right.
My Peter had already gone.
You were still
a father.
I saw how much
you loved him--
your strength.
Not strength--hubris.
And I've been punished
for it ever since.
Hmm.
By whom?
By God...
By a deity--
whatever you want
to call it.
And I understand
I deserve it.
No man should do
what I did.
You made a mistake.
That's what being a man is.
It was more
than a mistake.
I broke universes.
I asked for a sign
of forgiveness.
But I got nothing.
There is no absolution
for me.
Well, I don't believe that.
I forgive you, Walter.
I forgave you
a long time ago.
And if I can...
God can.
We both lost our sons.
We never watched them...
Grow up and...
Fall in love, have babies.
But there's
something of them in him.
This Peter.
I know you feel it too.
And if you could
just help him...
Walter, he deserves to go
back to the people he loves...
and who love him.
I'm afraid.
So is he.
(Seven)
We've got incoming.
Secure the cargo.
Hold them off.
Let's go.
[Gun cocks]
Hey, can I get
one of those?
- Think you'll need a gun?
- Better safe than sorry.
[Gun cocks]
Get down!
[Machine gun fire]
We are done here.
(Peter)
That's Jones.
(Olivia) Lincoln,
I'm going after Jones.
[Machine gun fire]
Give me your walkie.
What?
Give me your walkie, now!
Notify Colonel Broyles
on the other side.
Have him to send a team
to meet me.
Olivia, stop!
Do not follow Jones!
The window will close
behind him.
And if it closes
while you're going through it,
it will kill you!
Olivia, please, trust me.
Olivia?
I'm here.
You okay?
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm okay.
Seems only hours ago
that I asked Peter
to be my emissary.
I knew that,
despite the accord,
that there remained
a great deal of...
Distrust and trepidation
between our sides--
much of it
directed towards me.
I also know the truth--
that a new breed
of shape-shifter
had infiltrated
both our worlds.
And the only way
to defeat them
meant working together,
fully combining
our resources
and our talents.
I thought that if you
heard this from someone
more impartial...
You'd see the imperative.
That message
is no longer necessary.
We know who
our enemy is now.
And that in itself
is a distinct step forward.
Now that we know that Jones
can cross between sides,
we can coordinate
our search.
You'll have
our complete support.
That's all good,
but you said
that only a tiny amount
of this processed mineral
is enough to tear a hole
through a universe.
So what
is he planning?
As far as we can tell,
he's already recovered
at least 100 pounds of it.
She's right.
We'll have to start
trying to game-plan
what he's after.
How?
We have no information
to work from,
and so far, he's been ahead
of us every step of the way.
Jones figured
we'd realize
he was interested
in the quarry,
so he crossed over
to the other side.
We recovered
his transport device.
Yes, but for all we know,
he has more of them.
He is holding
all the cards on this.
(Peter)
Not all of them.
You have me.
I know him.
And I saw how nervous he was
when I was questioning him.
If nothing else,
I'm a variable
that he didn't plan for.
So, yes, we will all have
to work together.
But somewhere,
we stopped him once before.
And we can stop
him again.
Okay, you have to tell me
everything you know
about David Robert Jones--
the one that you encountered.
- Of course.
Okay, like, every little detail
that you remember.
[Chuckles]
Sure.
All right, I'm gonna see
what rooms are available.
What? Now?
We should get started
right away.
No, let's
do this tomorrow.
I feel like I haven't slept
in three days.
First thing, I promise.
Fair enough.
You know, Peter, uh...
Before, at the quarry,
if it weren't for you...
You're welcome.
All right, I'll have someone
pick you up in the morning.
[Knock on door]
Yeah, yeah, I hear ya.
[Knocking continues]
Walter.
Are you okay?
- May I come inside?
- Yeah, yeah.
Perhaps something
to drink--
it's quite a long walk.
Thank you.
You should know
that your mother
was a wonderful woman...
Every version of her.
She came to see you.
I lost the people
I loved most,
and I imagine
you miss them too--
the people
you've left behind.
Yes, I do.
I'll help you, Peter.
I will help you
get home.
The last 25 years
I've spent thinking
about losing my son.
I thought I was
an expert on loss.
Maybe that's
why you're here...
Mm, because
there are still things
that I need to learn.
[Chuckles softly]
What?
I just spent
the last several days
with the other Walter.
And I was very surprised
to learn
that he's not the man
that I thought he was.
But I am not at all surprised
to learn that you are.
Is that a good thing?
Yes, Walter.
That is a very good thing.
You know,
I used to live here.
[Whirring, keys clacking]
[Computer beeping rapidly]
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
Tip for download: Open Subtitles MKV Player